Guide to Otesaga Hotel and Iroquois Farm staff photographs, 1917-1922.
Fenimore Art Museum
Otesaga Hotel and Iroquois Farm staff photographs, 1917-1922.
.25 cu. ft. (113 b&w photos, 2 ¾” x 4 ½”)
Unknown
Fenimore Art Museum Research Library 80 Lake Road Cooperstown, NY 13326
Coll. No. 463
NM-6.93
Acquisition Information
Coll. No. 463 is open for research according to the regulations of Fenimore Art Museum Library.
Access Restrictions
In 1910, Gertrude, Ruth, and Mary Wood, three of the seven children of Byron and Emily J. Wood, lived in Marbletown, Ulster County, NY.
Biography/History
Photographs.; Cooperstown (Otsego County, N.Y.); Leatherstocking Falls (Cooperstown, N.Y.); Three Mile Point (Cooperstown,N.Y.); The Otesaga Hotel The Otesaga Hotel (Cooperstown, Otsego County, NY).; Iroquois Farm (Cooperstown, Otsego County, NY).; Masters, Mary Wood, b. 1896.; McDonough, Gertrude Wood, 1898-1983.; Thornblade, Ruth Wood, 1900-1987.; Cooperstown (N.Y.)--Social life and customs--Pictorial works.; Cooperstown (N.Y.)--History.; Hotels--Employees.
Black and white photographs of the staff of Cooperstown’s Otsesaga Hotel and Iroquois Farm posing in groups of up to 20 at various, mostly rural locations in the vicinity of Cooperstown, Otsego County, NY. All but a few of the photos are labeled by date and location. If Gertrude Wood McDonough, Ruth Wood Thornblade, and/or Mary Wood Masters appear in photos, they are identified. Some photos feature autos, horses, a duck pond, women in maid’s uniforms and in costumes, and various Cooperstown landmarks.
Scope and Contents
The collection of 113 photographs is arranged chronologically and identified by location and person, if apparent.
- 463.1/1 Grey Mouse Farm, September 10, 1917
- 463.1/2 Cooperstown, July 9, 1920
- 463.1/3 Cooperstown, July 15, 1920
- 463.1/4 Cooperstown, July 16, 1920
- 463.1/5 Cooperstown, Leatherstocking Falls, July 20, 1920
- 463.1/6 Cooperstown, July 21, 1920
- 463.1/7 Cooperstown, August 5, 1920
- 463.1/8 Cooperstown, August 20, 1920
- 463.1/9 Three Mile Point, Guy's Farm, Guy's Flower Garden, September 19, 1920
- 463.1/10 Iroquois Farm, September 15, 1920
- 463.1/11 Cooperstown, 1921
- 463.1/12 Cooperstown, 1922
- 463.1/13 Cooperstown, Unknown
- 463.1/14 Unknown location